Parapsychology Laboratory Records, 1893-1984
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Correspondence Series, 1893 and 1919-1984., 380 containers (190 lin. ft.)
  - 1976
    - Mundle, C.W.K. (Box 354)
    - N - P, (3 folders) (Box 354)
    - Parapsychological Association (Box 354)
    - Q - Rz, (2 folders) (Box 354)
    - Rao, K.R. (Box 354)
    - Sa - Sz, (2 folders) (Box 355)
    - Special Children (Box 355)
    - T - Z, (2 folders) (Box 355)
  - 1977
    - A (Box 355)
    - American Society for Psychical Research (Box 355)
    - B (Box 355)
    - Boles, Norma (Box 355)
    - C - D (Box 355)
    - E - J, (3 folders) (Box 356)
    - John F. Kennedy University (Box 356)
    - Lyle, Charles E. (Box 356)
    - K - L (Box 356)
    - M - O, (2 folders) (Box 356)
    - P (Box 357)
    - Parapsychological Association (Box 357)
    - Q - Sz, (3 folders) (Box 357)
    - Southern Region Parapsychology Association (Box 357)
    - Swann, Isabelle (Box 357)
    - T - Z, (2 folders) (Box 357)
  - 1978
    - A - D, (3 folders) (Box 357)
    - E - F (Box 358)
    - Forms (Box 358)
    - Foundations Concerned With Parapsychology (Box 358)
    - G - M, (4 folders) (Box 358)
    - Maurin Foundation (Box 358)
    - N - P (Box 358)
    - Parapsychological Association (Box 358)
    - Q - R (Box 358)
    - Research Associates Reports (Box 358)
    - S (Box 358)
    - Smithsonian Institution (Box 359)
    - Southern Regional Parapsychological Association (Box 359)
    - T - Z, (2 folders) (Box 359)
  - 1979
    - A (Box 359)
    - American Association for the Advancement of Science (Box 359)
    - American Society for Psychical Research (Box 359)
    - B (Box 359)
    - Bevan, William (Box 359)
    - C (Box 359)
    - Cox, W.E. (Box 359)
    - D (Box 359)
    - Dictaphone Corporation (Box 359)
    - E - F (Box 359)
    - Films (Box 359)
    - G - H, (2 folders) (Box 359)
    - I - N, (4 folders) (Box 360)
    - Neville, Enrique (Box 360)
    - O - P (Box 360)
    - Parapsychological Association (Box 360)
    - Q - S, (2 folders) (Box 360)
    - Science (Box 360)
    - Southeastern Regional Parapsychological Association (Box 360)
    - T - Z (Box 361)
    - Wheeler Affair (Box 361)
  - 1980,A - Z, (1 folder) (Box 361)
  - Condolence Letters, (3 folders) (Box 361)
  - 1980,Condolence Letters, (2 folders) (Box 362)
  - J.B. Rhine Memorial Service (Box 362)
  - Tribute to J.B. Rhine (Box 362)
  - 1981,A - Z (Box 362)
  - 1982,A - Z (Box 362)
  - 1983,A - Z (Box 362)
  - L.E. Rhine Memorial Service (Box 362)
  - 1984,Rogo-Levy Affair (Box 362)
  - Legal Papers:
    - Contract with Haines House of Cards (Box 362)
    - Contracts with Publishers (1954-1979) (Box 362)
    - Contracts with Publishers (1954-1979) (Box 363)
    - Copyright ESP Cards (1955-1971) (Box 363)
  - Legal Matters:
    - Copyright Beckman, Dickinson and Co. (Box 363)
    - Tradeworks (1937-1971) (Box 363)
  - Mail Lists for Complimentary Books and Articles (1948-1968), (3 folders) (Box 363)
  - 1984, Personnel (1967-1977), (5 folders) (Box 364)
  - Visas (Exchange Visitor Program) (Box 364)
- Research Files Series, 1912-1917and 1937-1963, 235 containers (117.5 lin. ft.)
  Mainly experimental records of work at the Parapsychology Laboratory, but also records of persons working elsewhere, and some personal and professional correspondence of laboratory staff members. There are four subseries:
  - Alphanumeric Files, 1933-1940
    Includes much of the earliest research, including most of what survives relating to the work published in Extra-Sensory Perception (1934). Several related files appear in other series. A contemporary index (c.1939) and other cards at the end provide some clues to the origin and purpose of the arrangement. Arranged in alphanumeric order.
    - A1. Stuart, C.S. 600 Dice PK, 1935-1936 (Box 365)
    - A3. Pratt, J.G. 96 Dice PK, 1935 (Box 365)
    - A7. Rhine, J.B. Hypnosis and PK, undated (Box 365)
    - A8. Smith, Burke M. PKS on Sealed Packs, 1935(?) (Box 365)
    - A9. Leeds, Morton ASPR PK, 1943 (Box 365)
    - A9a. McDougall, William Dice PK, 1934 (Box 365)
    - A16. Rhine, J.B. Preliminary PK Experiments, 1935 (Box 365)
    - A19. Rhine, J.B. PK Double, 1935-1942 (Box 365)
    - B1. Woodruff, J.L. Campus Precog PDT News Cuts, 1938 (Box 365)
    - B2. Woodruff, J.L. Carr Experiment, 1937 (Box 365)
    - B3. Woodruff, J.L. Distance Precog, 1937, (2 folders) (Box 365)
    - B3. Woodruff, J.L. Distance Precog, 1938 (Box 366)
    - B4-5. Woodruff, J.L. Music Experiment, 1937, (2 folders) (Box 366)
    - B6. Woodruff, J.L. Dice PDT, 1936-1938 (Box 366)
    - B7. Woodruff, J.L. Misc. ESP (Box 366)
    - B8. Woodruff, J.L. Personality Class ESP, 1938 (Box 366)
    - B9. Woodruff, J.L. Distance ESP at ?, undated (Box 366)
    - B10. Woodruff, J.L. and Snyder W. PS Project, 1937 (Box 366)
    - B11. Woodruff, J.L. Correspondence Experiment, 1937, (2 folders) (Box 366)
    - B12. Zirkle, George Light Machine, 1936 (Box 367)
    - B13. Zirkle, Sara Lever Machine, 1936 (Box 367)
    - B14. Zirkle, George Dice Machine ESP, 1936 (Box 367)
    - B15. Zirkle, George Novelty and Variety DT, 1936 (Box 367)
    - B16. Zirkle, George Reflective Choice, 1936 (Box 367)
    - B17. Zirkle, George Hypnosis and ESP, 1936 (Box 367)
    - B18. Zirkle, Sara Semi-automatic DT, undated (Box 367)
    - B19. Rhine, J.B. Survey for Subjects, 1934 (Box 367)
    - B20. Rhine, J.B. Unsummarized ESP, 1934-1935 (Box 367)
    - B21. Zirkle, Sara BT - DT, 1934 (Box 367)
    - B22. Rhine, J.B. RDT, undated (Box 367)
    - B23. Rhine, L.E. Distance ESP, 1937 (Box 367)
    - B24. Zirkle, Sara PDT, DT, BT, 1934 (Box 367)
    - B25. Zirkle, Sara DPT, 1934 (Box 367)
    - B26. Zirkle, Sara PT, 1934 (Box 367)
    - B27. McDougall, William Unsummarized ESP, 1933-1934 (Box 368)
    - B28. Pratt, J.G. Correspondence PDT, undated (Box 368)
    - B29. Pratt, J.G. DT vs. PDT, undated (Box 368)
    - B30. Price, M.M. Psychotic ESP, 1935-1938 (Box 368)
    - B31. Woodruff, J.L. ESP, 1937 (Box 368)
    - C1. Rhine, J.B. PT, 1937 (Box 368)
    - C2. Rhine J.B. Sealed Pack, 1936 (Box 368)
    - C3. Sealed Pack, 1934 (Box 368)
    - C4. Rhine, J.B. Sealed Pack #2, 1937 (Box 368)
    - C5. Pratt, J.G. Sealed Pack, 1936 (Box 368)
    - C6. McFarland, J.D. Psychic Shuffle, 1938 (Box 368)
    - C7. Pratt, J.G. Psychic Shuffle, undated (Box 368)
    - C8. Warner, Lucien. Role of Luck, undated (Box 368)
    - C9. Sharp, Vernon and Eunice. Sealed Pack, 1937 (Box 368)
    - C10. Pegram, M.H. Sealed Pack, 1936 (Box 368)
    - C11. Sealed Pack, 1936 (Box 368)
    - C12. Rhine, J.B. Sealed Pack, 1936 (Box 368)
    - C13. Stuart, C.E. Sealed Pack, 1937 (Box 368)
    - C14. Hutchinson, Dall. Sealed Pack, 1937 (Box 368)
    - C16. Rice, C. Hilton. Sealed Pack, 1936-1937 (Box 368)
    - C17. Gibson, E.P. Sealed Pack, 1936-1937 (Box 368)
    - C18. Codes on Old Packs for Checking, undated, 1938 (Box 369)
    - C19. Gibson, E.P. Sealed Pack, 1936-1937 (Box 369)
    - C20. Gibson, E.P. Sealed Pack, 1936-1937 (Box 369)
    - C21. Sealed Pack Recheck– Occurrence of scoring errors, 1938(?) (Box 369)
    - C22. Rhine, J.B. and Stuart, C.S. Sealed Pack, 1936 (Box 369)
    - C23. Rhine, J.B. Sealed Pack, 1937 (Box 369)
    - C24. Gibson, E.P. Sealed Pack Summary, 1938 (Box 369)
    - C25. Smith, Burhem and Pegram, M.H. Sealed Pack, 1936 (Box 369)
    - C26. Gibson, E.P. Sealed Pack, 1936-1937 (Box 369)
    - C27. Price, Peggy and Pegram, M.H. Sealed Pack, undated (Box 369)
    - C28. Rhine, J.B. Sealed Pack General Summary, 1938 (Box 369)
    - C32. Rhine, J.B. Eileen Garrett, 1934 (Box 369)
    - C33. Rhine, J.B. Correspondence with Subjects, 1933 (Box 369)
    - C33. Rhine, J.B. ESP Reported Dates, 1933, (2 folders) (Box 369)
    - C34. Rhine, J.B. First Precognition Paper, 1934-1935 (Box 369)
    - C34. Rhine, J.B. First Precognition Paper, 1934-1937, (15 folders) (Box 370)
    - C34A. Price, Margaret M. Oxford Experiments, 1937 (Box 371)
    - C34B. Pegram, M.H. Raleigh Experiment, 1937 (Box 371)
    - C34C. Price, M.M. Miscellaneous Dates, 1937-1938 (Box 371)
    - C34D. Price, M.M. After P. P. Experiment, 1938 (Box 371)
    - C35. McCracken. Sealed Pack, 1937 (Box 371)
    - C36. Price, M.M. Raleigh Blind Data, 1937, (2 folders) (Box 371)
    - C37. Price, M.M. Tables for Paper, 1937 (Box 371)
    - C38. Rhine, J.B. ESP Tests with Enclosed Cards (Box 371)
    - C39. Pratt, J.G. and Woodruff, J.L. STM 2400 Run Cross-Check, undated (Box 371)
    - C40. Rhine, J.B. Precog Series Cross-Check, undated (Box 371)
    - D1. Rhine, J.B. Psychic Shuffle Summary, 1938 (Box 371)
    - D2. Weckesser, Miriam. Psychic Shuffle, 1938 (Box 371)
    - D3. Weckesser, Miriam. Psychic Shuffle, 1938 (Box 371)
    - D4. Pegram, M.M. Psychic Shuffle, 1938 (Box 371)
    - D5a. Smith, Burlee M. Psychic Shuffle, 1936 (Box 372)
    - D6. Buck-Michaelson, G.E. Psychic Shuffle, 1936 (Box 372)
    - D8. Stuart, C.E. Psychic Shuffle, 1937 (Box 372)
    - D9. Woodruff, J.L. Psychic Shuffle, 1937 (Box 372)
    - D12. Pratt, J.G. Psychic Shuffle, 1935 (Box 372)
    - D13. Woodruff, J.L. Psychic Shuffle, 1937-1938 (Box 372)
    - D14. Dickerson, J. Psychic Shuffle, 1938 (Box 372)
    - D15. McCartney. Psychic Shuffle (Box 372)
    - D16. Pegram, M.H. Psychic Shuffle, undated (Box 372)
    - D17. Pegram, M.H. Psychic Shuffle, undated (Box 372)
    - D18. Rhine, J.B. PDT, 1936 (Box 372)
    - D19. McFarland, J.D. GESP–DT–PDT, 1937 (Box 372)
    - D20. Pegram, M.H. and McFarland, J.D. PDT, 1934 (Box 372)
    - D22. Sharp, E. and V. PDT (Box 372)
    - D23. Price, M.H. PDT, undated (Box 372)
    - D24a. Rhine, J.B. Precognition News Cuts, 1937, (2 folders) (Box 372)
    - D56. Pratt, J.G. and Smith, Burke. Psychic Shuffle, 1937 (Box 372)
    - D26. Cragsmoor ESP, 1935 (Box 373)
    - D27. Rhine, J.B. Precognition News Cuts, 1937(?) (Box 373)
    - D28. Pegram, Margaret H. Lillian Barber msc., 1936 (Box 373)
    - D29. Pegram, Margaret H. N.C. College for Negroes (NCCN), 1936 (Box 373)
    - D29a. Pegram, Margaret H. NCCN: DT Summary, 1937(?) (Box 373)
    - D30a.-D31. Pegram, Margaret H. NCCN, 1937, (2 folders) (Box 373)
    - D32. Pegram, Margaret H. ESP Data, undated (Box 373)
    - D33.-D40. Pegram, Margaret H. NCCN, 1936-1937, (9 folders) (Box 373)
    - D41. Pegram, Margaret H. DT, 1936-1937 (Box 373)
    - D42. Pegram, Margaret H. NCCN, 1936-1937 (Box 373)
    - D43. Pegram, M.H. NCCN, 1936 (Box 373)
    - D44. Pegram, M.H. DT, 1936 (Box 373)
    - D45. Pegram, M.H. NCCN DT, 1936 (Box 373)
    - D46. Pegram, M.H. Children at CHP DT, 1935 (Box 373)
    - D47. Pegram, M.H. Wright Refuge Data (Box 373)
    - D48. Pegram, M.H. ESP Data, 1934 (Box 373)
    - D49. Pegram, M.H. Pauline Pegram Notebooks, undated, (3 folders) (Box 374)
    - D50.-D51. Pegram, M.H. ESP Data, 1934 and undated, (2 folders) (Box 374)
    - D52. Pegram, M.H. Misc. Dice PK, 1935 (Box 374)
    - D53. Pegram, M.H. DT and Skip, 1936-1937 (Box 374)
    - D54. Pegram, M.H. ESP Data, 1937 (Box 374)
    - D55. Pegram, M.H. Duke-California LD GESP, 1935-1936 (Box 374)
    - D56. Pegram, M.H. Recent Scientific Evidence for Survival, 1937 (Box 374)
    - D57. Pegram, M.H. Bradshaw Data, 1937 (Box 374)
    - D58. Pegram, M.H. Bradshaw Data, 1937 (Box 375)
    - E1.-E43. Gibson, E.P. ESP Series 1-48, 1935-1936, (11 folders) (Box 375)
    - E12. Gibson, E.P. ESP Series 49-80, 1936-1938, (32 folders) (Box 376)
    - E44. Gibson, E.P. Summer Series 1-80, 1935-1938 (Box 376)
    - E45. Gibson, E.P. ESP Series 81: RBM Distance, 1938 (Box 377)
    - E46. Gibson, E.P. Psychic Shuffle Summary, 1938 (Box 377)
    - E47. Gibson, E.P. Underdeveloped Negative Control Summary, 1938 (Box 377)
    - E48. Gibson, E.P. 12.2 B.M. of Jaro + less, 1936 (Box 377)
    - E49. Gibson, E.P. Summaries of PM Distance Series 82-85, 1938-Spring (Box 377)
    - E50. Chervenka, E. Olivet College Series 1-2 (Box 377)
    - E51. Chervenka, E. Mized Experiments- Series 3 (Box 377)
    - E59. Gibson, E.P. and Stuart, C.E. ESP Experiment in G.R., 1935-1936 (Box 377)
    - E61. Gibson, E.P. ESP Series 83, 1938 (Box 377)
    - E66. Riess, B.E. Distance GESP, 1937 (Box 377)
    - E66a. Cross Check of 74 Run Series, 1939 (Box 377)
    - E67. Gibson, E.P. DT Data of L.H.G., 1938 (Box 377)
    - E68. Chervenka, E. Series A, 1938 (Box 377)
    - E69. Woodruff, J.L. Symbol Size ESP, 1938 (Box 377)
    - E70. Woodruff, J.L. STM (B. + L.), 1938 (Box 377)
    - E72. Rhine, J.B. and Ownley, Sara Lake Junaluska Distance ESP, 1933 (Box 377)
    - E73. Gibson, E.P. Distance DT-PDT, 1938 (Box 377)
    - E76. Rhine, J.B. Adult-Child Precognition, 1940 (Box 378)
    - E76. Rhine, J.B. Non-PK Precognition Summaries, 1940 (Box 378)
    - F9. Rhine, J.B. BM (Box 378)
    - F10. Rhine, L.E. and Pratt, J.G. Precognition Experiment, 1938-1939 (Box 378)
    - F11. Rhine, J.B. Pre-Matching, 1938 (Box 378)
    - F11a. Rhine, J.B. Pre-Matching, 1938 (Box 379)
    - F12. Rhine, J.B. Precognition DC (Box 379)
    - F13. Rhine, J.B. PM, 1938? (Box 379)
    - F14. Rhine, J.B. Sealed B.M., 1938? (Box 379)
    - F15. Rhine, J.B. Reward Precognition (Box 379)
    - F16. Crampton and Smith, B.M. (Box 380)
    - F17. Smith, B.M. and Pratt, J.G. STM, 1939 (Box 380)
    - F18. Pratt, J.G. and Woodruff, J.L. STM, 1939 (Box 380)
    - F19. Pratt-Woodruff, 1940 (Box 380)
    - F19. Pratt-Woodruff, 1940, (3 folders) (Box 381)
    - F20. Hutchinson-Pratt DT-PDT, 1940, (2 folders) (Box 381)
    - F21.-F22. Pratt, J.G. and Woodruff, J.L. PM, 1940, (2 folders) (Box 382)
    - F22a. Pratt, J.G. and Woodruff, J.L. Low Aim, 1940 (Box 382)
    - F23. Rhine, J.B. and Gibson, E.P. PDT (Music) (Box 382)
    - F24. Rhine, J.B. and Gibson, E.P. PDT Music, Introspection, 1939 (Box 382)
    - F25. Stuart, L.E. Dice cnt PDT, 1936 (Box 382)
    - F27. Siegel, P.S. Shock Experiment, 1939-1940 (Box 383)
    - F?. Hutchinson, L. PDT, 1940 (Box 383)
  - Subject Files, 1934-1960
    Files grouped according to experimental subject or research domain. Includes much of the early resarch on psychokinesis (PK) and much of the early displacement analysis. Also includes work of Karlo Marchesi, both as experimenter and subject, and records of 1945 C. E. Stuart work with Eileen Garrett. Arranged alphabetically by subject, then chronologically.
    - Displacement (Box 384)
      - Pratt, J.G. Displacement Effects, 1949 (Box 384)
      - Pratt, J.G. C.J. analyses, 1950, (11 folders) (Box 384)
      - Pratt, J.G. C.J. analyses, 1950, (2 folders) (Box 385)
      - Pratt, J.G. D.W. analyses, 1950, (6 folders) (Box 385)
      - Pratt, J.G. Colorado analyses, 1950, (3 folders) (Box 385)
      - Pratt, J.G. Soal B.S. analyses, 1951, (3 folders) (Box 386)
      - Pratt, J.G. Soal Stewart analyses, 1951-1952, (6 folders) (Box 386)
      - Pratt, J.G. Soal Stewart analyses, 1951-1952, (12 folders) (Box 387)
      - Pratt, J.G. Soal Stewart analyses, 1951-1952, (8 folders) (Box 388)
      - Pratt, J.G. Soal Stewart analyses, 1951-1952, (5 folders) (Box 389)
    - Garrett, E.
      - Stuart, C.E.? Dice vs Chips, 1945 (Box 389)
      - Stuart, C.E.? ESP and PK Summary Sheets, 1945 (Box 389)
      - Stuart, C.E.? Help-hinder, 1945, (4 folders) (Box 389)
      - Stuart, C.E.? Light-dark Comparison, 1945 (Box 389)
      - Stuart, C.E.? Miscellaneous, 1945 (Box 389)
      - Stuart, C.E.? Precognition Drawings, 1945 (Box 389)
      - Stuart, C.E.? Precognition Numbers, 1945 (Box 389)
      - Stuart, C.E.? Selected ESP Trials, 1945 (Box 389)
      - Stuart, C.E.? Three-sender GESP, 1945 (Box 389)
      - Stuart, C.E. Trance Study, 1945, (7 folders) (Box 390)
      - Two Target PK Series, 1945 (Box 390)
    - Marchesi, K. (Box 391)
      - Unwitnessed DT Trials, 1939 (Box 391)
      - Transoceanic ESP Exp., 1939-1940, (3 folders) (Box 391)
      - Second Zagreb-Durham Exp., 1946-1947, (2 folders) (Box 391)
      - Clairvoyance Drawing Test, 1948 (Box 391)
      - One Year Precognition Exp., 1948-1949, (3 folders) (Box 391)
      - U.S. Experiments, 1950, (5 folders) (Box 392)
    - Psychokinesis
      - Reeves, M.P. Double 1's and 6's, 1934 (Box 392)
      - Hilton, H.H. and Baer. High Dice, 1934, (2 folders) (Box 392)
      - Hilton, H.H. and Rhine, J.B. High Dice, 1934(Folder 1) (Box 392)
      - Hilton, H.H. and Rhine, J.B. High Dice, 1934(Folder 2) (Box 393)
      - Rhine, L.E. and Rhine, J.B. High Dice, 1934-1935 (Box 393)
      - Reeves, M.P. High and Low Dice, 1934, (2 folders) (Box 393)
      - Frick, H. Series 1, 1934-1935, (2 folders) (Box 393)
      - Smith, F. Series 1 and 2, 1934-1935, (2 folders) (Box 393)
      - Gibson, E.P. and Rhine, J.B. Grand Rapids Series, 1935 (Box 394)
      - McDougall, W. One Dice Series, 1935 (Box 394)
      - Frick, H.L. Series 2, 1935-1936 (Box 394)
      - Gibson, E.P. and Gibson, L.H. Series 2, 1935-1937, (2 folders) (Box 394)
      - Price, M.M and Woodruff, J.L. Social effect study, 1936 (Box 394)
      - Rhine, J.B. Cup-Machine Comparison, 1936 (Box 394)
      - Rhine, J.B. and Averill, R.L. Effect of caffeine, 1936 (Box 394)
      - Rhine, J.B. and Averill, R.L. Effect of alcohol, 1936 (Box 394)
      - Rhine, J.B. and Woodruff, J.L. Red vs. white dice, 1936 (Box 394)
      - Rhine, J.B. and Woodruff, J.L. Small vs. medium dice, 1936 (Box 394)
      - Woodruff, J.L. and Wiemokly, Van. Big and little dice, 1936 (Box 394)
      - Woodruff, J.L. and Reeves, M.P. Six by six, 1936-1937, (5 folders) (Box 395)
      - Frick, H.L. 60-dice series, 1937 (Box 395)
      - Gibson, E.P., Gibson, L.H. and Rhine, J.B. 3-dice series, 1937 (Box 395)
      - Woodruff, J.L. L. E. series, 1937, (2 folders) (Box 395)
    - Card file: (Box 396)
      - ESP, PK, Precog., PS, PT, Miscellaneous. (Box 396)
      - Gibson, E.P. Doubles, 1942 (Box 397)
      - Herter, C.J. and Rhine, J.B. Exploratory study, 1942 (Box 397)
      - Gatling, W. Around-the-Die, 1943 (Box 397)
      - Waller, D. Distance PK, 1944, (2 folders) (Box 397)
      - Pope, Gladys. Clairvoyance drawings, undated, (2 folders) (Box 397)
      - Sex Identification Cards, 1961 (Box 398)
    - Sex prediction. Edward Gale data, 1959-1960 (Box 398)
    - Willeys.
      - Distance ESP, 1948 (Box 398)
      - Known-unknown precognition, 1948, (2 folders) (Box 398)
    - Card File: Sex Prediction Data (Box 399)
    - Willeys. (Box 400)
      - Precognition work, 1949, (2 folders) (Box 400)
      - “Clairvoyance” series, 1941, (4 folders) (Box 400)
      - One-year precognition, 1950, (2 folders) (Box 400)
      - “Clairvoyance” names and symbols, 1950(2) (Box 400)
      - Lab tests, 1951 (Box 400)
  - Experimenter Files, 1912-1965
    Largest subseries consisting of files grouped by experimenter, containing correspondence, data, and analyses. The earliest records (1912-17) are laboratory notebooks of J. E. Coover of Stanford University. Most files relate to research conducted at the Parapsychology Laboratory, but many files contain records of outside researchers. The latter files are usually grouped with the files of the laboratory staff member who was responsible for supervising these persons or developing research reports based on their work.
    - Adams, E. Words vs. symbols, 1941 (Box 401)
    - Aiken, U. Interesting vs. uninteresting targets, 1948(4) (Box 401)
    - Anderson, M.
      - ESP trials, 1955-1956 (Box 401)
      - Tests with Rhea White, 1955-1956, (2 folders) (Box 401)
      - Tests with Rhea White, 1955-1956 (Box 402)
      - A-W instructions, 1956? (Box 402)
      - A-W 1 series, 1956, (5 folders) (Box 402)
      - A-W 2 series, 1956, (2 folders) (Box 402)
      - A-W 2 series, 1956 (Box 403)
      - A-W 3 series, 1956, (4 folders) (Box 403)
      - Boys' training school tests, 1956(3) (Box 403)
      - Classroom ESP?, 1956 (Box 404)
      - ESP trials, 1956 (Box 404)
      - Rose Hynes precognition trials, 1956 (Box 404)
      - Letters from Rhea White, 1956 (Box 404)
      - Miscellaneous, 1956 and undated (Box 404)
      - Miscellaneous data, 1956 (Box 404)
      - Trials with Marguerite Linsert, 1956 (Box 404)
      - Precognition trials, 1956-58 (Box 404)
      - Precognition trials, 1956-58 (Box 405)
      - Classroom ESP?, 1957 (Box 405)
      - Hillsboro test, 1957(, (5 folders) (Box 405)
      - Hillsboro test, 1957, (6 folders) (Box 406)
      - Hillsboro test, 1957, (2 folders) (Box 407)
      - Missouri experiment, 1957, (4 folders) (Box 407)
      - St. Charles test, 1957, (2 folders) (Box 407)
      - St. Charles test, 1957, (4 folders) (Box 408)
      - San Diego procog. tests, 1957, (4 folders) (Box 408)
      - San Diego precog. tests, 1957, (3 folders) (Box 409)
      - Wheaton tests (MA 1), 1957, (3 folders) (Box 409)
      - Wheaton tests (MA 1), 1957, (4 folders) (Box 410)
      - Angstadt data, 1957-1958 (Box 410)
      - McLaughlin music experiment, 1959(2) (Box 410)
      - New Mexico clairvoyance tests, 1959 (Box 411)
      - Tests with Nan Gerding, 1959 (Box 411)
      - Wheaton tests, 1959 (Box 411)
      - Positive scoring series, undated (Box 411)
      - Clock targets, undated (Box 411)
      - ESP test packets, undated (Box 411)
      - Martha Minter trials, undated (Box 411)
      - Miscellaneous data, undated, (2 folders) (Box 411)
      - Miscellaneous questionnaires, undated (Box 411)
      - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 411)
      - Page Literary Society tests, undated(2) (Box 411)
      - Study of values and ESP, undated (Box 411)
      - Washington, D.C., tests, undated (Box 411)
    - Bates E. (Box 412)
      - ESP card tests, 1950 (Box 412)
      - Personality questionnaries, 1950, (2 folders) (Box 412)
      - Chautaugua experiment, 1951 (Box 412)
      - Bell-Jacobs experiment, 1945 (Box 412)
    - Bell, May
      - ESP, 1948-1949 (Box 412)
      - ESP shuffle, 1951 (Box 412)
      - SSD-SBD, undated (Box 412)
    - Bevan, J. (Box 413)
      - Sheep-goat experiment, 1946, (2 folders) (Box 413)
      - Card runs-machine tape, 1946 (Box 413)
      - Sheep-goat record sheets, 1946 (Box 413)
      - ESP test record sheets, 1947 (Box 413)
      - ESP series 3, 1947 (Box 413)
      - Dice tests, 1947 (Box 414)
      - Davidson College series, 1948, (2 folders) (Box 414)
      - ESP record sheets, undated, (3 folders) (Box 414)
      - ESP score sheets, undated (Box 414)
      - Free response drawnings, undated, (2 folders) (Box 414)
      - Clairvoyance targets, undated (Box 414)
    - Bevan, W. Heidelberg College study, 1948, (5 folders) (Box 415)
    - Bindrim, E.
      - Miscellaneous, 1946 (Box 415)
      - Exploratory drawing method, undated (Box 415)
    - Buck, A.
      - Dream reports, 1953, (2 folders) (Box 415)
      - Dream reports, 1952-1953, (3 folders) (Box 416)
    - Bugelski, R. Chance comparisons, 1939 (Box 416)
    - Burke, E.
      - Series 1002, 1949, (4 folders) (Box 416)
      - Series 1002, 1949, (4 folders) (Box 417)
    - Cadoret, R.
      - “System” ESP, 1952 (Box 417)
      - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 417)
    - Casper, G.
      - Marietta Newton tests, 1951 (Box 417)
      - Heidelberg College tests, 1951, (5 folders) (Box 417)
      - Heidelberg College tests, 1951, (4 folders) (Box 418)
    - Clement, A.
      - Data and notes, 1953, (2 folders) (Box 418)
      - Sally Rhine notes, 1945, 1953 (Box 418)
    - Coover, J.
      - Lotto-Block Guessing, 1912-1913 (Box 418)
      - Guessing of playing cards, 1912-1913 (Box 418)
      - Guessing of playing cards, 1913-1914(5 notebooks) (Box 419)
      - Playing Card Journal, 1913-1914(2 notebooks) (Box 420)
    - Cranmore, C.
      - PK experiment, 1947, (4 folders) (Box 420)
      - Comparison of decks, 1948, (2 folders) (Box 420)
      - Long distance ESP, 1948 (Box 420)
      - PK–drawing–ESP experiment, 1948, (2 folders) (Box 420)
    - Crumbaugh, J. Data analysis, undated (Box 421)
    - David, F. Comparison of cards, 1954 (Box 421)
    - Davidson, W.
      - First rat PK experiment, 1945 (Box 421)